Ok.
Good morning everyone thank you so much for coming and joining us today
and this is the
talk on hosted web apps and web platform innovations so-if bass the
...looking for your in the right room if you were looking for the other one and
talk the folks in the back and I'll give you the right direction so my name is jeff...and I'm
...xml and we're really excited talk to-you
about web apps today and specifically we're going to be spending a lot of time about...so
we think web apps should be simple to make.
They should feel familiar to web developers and they
should be powerful and that's what we're going to talk about today
ways to reuse the code that you already have.
Websites web apps that you've already built a frameworks
...already using of
...you already have and use that to build great apps on windows.
Just a little bit
...here submit evaluation and you have a chance to win a
prize.
I...know what that prizes but I'm sure it's exciting because it's from microsoft and we get a lot of
inciting stuff right now ok so this is the agenda that
we going through today we're going to just go over what a windows web app
is in whatyou know, what makes it out in app then we're going to spend a lot of time talking
about hosted web applications but we also want to talk about the changes that we have
...package web apps and the new web view that we have an windows
...as well and then we're going to end with tulane and talk about how some of the
changes to the platform are bringing innovation to the tooling as well?
All right so let's go ahead and get started with the windows ten.
So, windows ten apps we've been on a journey
two-one app platform for one windows so your apps run across
the multiple devices on the windows platform windows web apps
are part of the universal windows platform they'll run across
the multiple windows devices like the desktop mobile xbox.
The io t devices like hollow
...these are just universal windows apps if you make a posted web app
...run across universal windows
...web app is one of the universal apps that you can
write for windows and now.
We've talked a lot this week about the new microsoft edge
browser and how we have a brand new engine that runs
the edge engine that does the rendering and quite powerful and then
we also have a new shocker engine that runs javascript significantly
faster you have in the past so that's what runs the browser?
Now when we move into the application space we
...javascript application environment
that uses that same engine and uses the same javascript engine
two-run your applications so what you really have is you have a sandbox
application that runs exactly like we have...the browser so the same
at rendering engine the same javascript engine now what that allows you
to do is a developer is...this term on your own the best way
to run your web content you can run it as a packaged app
input all of your content inside of the app acts or you can now run it
as a hosted application where instead of packaging content
inside the app you're actually going to be pointing externally to your web
server and then of course you can also mix the environment's and have some of your
code running locally and some of the running on a web server windows ten gives us a
lot of flexibility for the developer for you to determine how
...vast uone two-run in package your code?
Now to kind of illustrate we are going to jump in and do a
bunch of demos of the hosted web apps and show you some really great examples of how this
...but we wanted to make it a little bit fine so instead of...
Having just hosted apps we wanted to have a hosted web app
jeopardy.
Which we call?
Hosted accuracy are you in I'm in
jeff okay already so for this I have a theme song.
And, I have one contestant that's you
...how create and excited let's do this how many plane the role of
...so I brought with me...a mustache.
A grave laser.
My wife would die she never sees medium blazers...online name tag.
Ok, let's get started so the board.
Creole my single contestant these are the categories
that you can choose from today sweets.
Okay, I think I'm going to start easy first I'm going to do child's play for a hundred
hours child's play for a hundred okay let's see what we have here
so child's play for a hundred this site is great
for kids of all ages...you must build a hosted app out of
nick dot com okay are you ready all take dot com and
...hosted at right.
Now well curls doing that I'm going to talk a
little bit about what he's going to be doing now a...
web app allows you as a developer to continue
with the workflows that you already have when you're writing for the web so we do
realize web developers write code in other places other
than visual studio so whether you're using visual studio your using sublime
...or whatever editor that-you...remember your writing code that's
publish for the web so you can continue to use the editor that you want?
Is quite ...for us is web developers to push our code to repost and
usually get repost that we store and get have or some other fantastic place
that still works remember your workflow for web is going to stay the same?
As well as your deployment model so remember it doesn't matter where
...deploying your code it doesn't matter what type of code you're using if
...web app is written in ruby or in java or in
no js you can continue to use that technology
because remember where utilizing the web apps you have on your server and when you put
that all together you end up with a rich windows application
that has all the feature visual of your website and we'll talk more about how
you can enable any of the windows api is that you can inside
of native application okay so let's go back?
...right rone contestant ...is time
to showed the work that you have done so I'll go ahead and move you.
To the right button...tell us what you've done.
...let me make it bigger rowboats...if I can.
...little one hundred-percent the bottom corner...screen.
...that which is that to like whatever you want it's amazing.
There you go awesome that's a little bigger so you guys...basically what I've done is
I've taken the website url for nick dot com just http.
Www dot nick dot com I've open the app
x manifest inside the standard windows ten javascript project this is
part of the blind template and I've replaced it with my website url so as the
star page I've given it nick dot com and there's one more thing that I had to do in order to
turn...dot com into a hosted web
app and what that was under application content...rules?
what these rules are they really define the container and where your web
app lives where the web begins so you you're able to define
the website urls better inside your app and the ones that are external to your app and
launch in a default browser so inside of here I've given nick dot com is one of the
urls this is my app and now all I have to do is hit run?
...run my application it's a hosted web app disappointing to the web and this is the
nick dot com website as an application on windows it's a great interactive say.
I can use my touch-screen to navigate through the content I can click
on games here I can see all the games and if I had time I go in and play a
game show you could do you think...a judges.
All right nice job...john okay,
back to the board.
Next category I think for this one I'm going to go a little higher I'm going to
...in seattle for two thousand
...in seattle for two thousand ok grill.
This site allows you to bring a friend with you when
you travel take can...so travel and build it into a hosted
web okay jeff...on the right and wow he does that.
Let's get back to a little...content now kroger's talk to-you about the.
The...you are rules that we have inside the manifest
the determines when your apps stops in when the internet
...so been a hosted app running code from a web
server it's quite common for us in our web code to have links to other places on
the web correct so we want-to make sure that a user
...site doesn't end up on the internet when they're inside of our app and that's what we
introduce the rules
it allows us to say this is the scope of our application when
you're online and nick dot com...it belongs inside the app is soon is
nick dot com links out to disney dot com or something like that which
they probably never do but link out to another site well then that's going to open up in the
users browser so it's really clearly defined where the internet starts and
where it ends now I additionally you can utilize these rules to determine
which parts of your app have access to the windows
...now we've talked about how you can use core time
...and I contacts in the xbox?
Integration but the truth is that any
windows api that's available in javascript can be access with
the hosted app from your web server so we're not limiting it to any particular api
were giving you access to the entire
set of them so as a web developer any feature you've ever desired to be over-doing
your web app we probably have an api to allow that so in the rules you
...you can determine that you're going to allow your website to access all the api is
all the windows api as you can specify
our allow for web only which we'll talk about a little bit later when we talk about the web
view but that basically allows you to...to only api is that you
expose from...native component in your app or you can specify...you can have certain api
...this is the default and specify that the urls.
In this particular rule do not have access to the windows aps and
...example so for...core tiny integration what you do is you add a
...cd file to
your web app so that's a voice command definition file and that's going to tell core...when
...particular phrases in opacity into your web app
...in javascript and the activation of your app you can pull
up the speech that was given to...and then determine what you want
to do with that your website so you have the ability to register that
...cd with core thailand and then react to the information...is backed here web
app through javascript okay so it looks like our contestant is ready.
Back to my role.
Are right...show us what you've done with friendliest in seattle?
Awesome.
...my screen jeff...negate.
Sweet so here's the code that I had to write for friends in seattle this is the can
...travel app it's a demo app that
I've demo website that I've written in the past so what I did is I just
said the star page and then as jeff mentioned in the application content your
...rules I've added this new tag the
windows runtime access tag and I've set the tag to all what that
does it gives javascript running on my server full access to the windows name space
when my website is running in the app container on windows and I'll go ahead and I'll show that app and
I've actually deployed on phone this time so this is running on this phone.
Go ahead and launch it.
Let load.
And, I was booking my travel to san francisco recently so let me do that.
Couple dates.
And, then I can choose a friend this is where the integration with the windows platform begins when I hit choose
of friend what I'm doing is I'm calling the windows name space and I'm calling the
picker api well
...you have one friend I do have one frame this huge.
Guess I really
...one friend away from being friend less in seattle that's right.
Okay, so, I can choose my friend in this case jeff were coming
...speak to-you all.
...confirm another integration point that I'm able to do is what the
calendar on windows and I can hit at to calendar and what that does is it pops the
native windows e for calendar I can pre populate the fields like
...san-francisco already and hit accept what that'll do is save
into my calendar and I'm all set to go and ready...book my trip and if my
...I wanted to you could also...notification?
Telling me that matrix has been...and there it is on my phone.
...judges on.
...running low on time so it is time for final app thirty.
And, your category is do it lives so what
that means is that you're going to have to code.
A website for us in front of us that
has in utilizes access to the windows aps.
Okay, jeff let me pull up project that I made the website that I'm going to pick is just
a code and I wrote so this is just a code
...on the web its publicly accessible.
Give it some time to load in visual studio.
There it is you guys can see it as well
I'm going to hit run so that it all run as an application...hosted web application on windows.
And, as it does that.
There it is the code...loaded I can write wide coding here added code
and add code of already done integration for the windows system
prompt calling doing feature detection for the windows namespaces
...calling directly into it but now so you how to add
integration with people picker the earlier api that I showed in my app.
So, I'll go to the browser...browser.
And, I've got some code
...already upon it's a publicly public available just doing feature detection
and calling into the contact picker...copy and paste that code.
Into my code...
So, all I have to do is that a new function.
And, pace that feature detection code...into the picker rate in it.
We mention we're not quite...with windows.
People quicker function.
And, hopefully this time.
...code there'd is so all I have to do is add another
button this one's for the system prompt but I'll add one for the...people picker.
Call the...function.
On the on click.
Actually what's going on as...live debugging in script.
There we go if...hits system prompt there
...a popped open the people picker live insider code
...did onstage what you think the awesome we think.
All right so we're having a little fine...the truth is that it is
sample to build a hosted application and what that allows you to do is
to spend your time developing your web app and then we
make the code part real easy a little bit configuration to
turn that on so we're going to jump over and we're going to talk a little bit about the package
javascript applications and some of the changes that we have in that space as well?
Okay, so,
a package javascript application is when you have your javascript code
...you loaded inside the app...so, for example, I'll have html javascript
css files it'll actually live inside of my package and wow it's
...the package wegive
...access to all of the windows universal api
is and it is delivered through the store so it's inside your affects that's uploaded
into the store and the users...download your entire app you need additional data you
make service calls to go out and load that...data
your packaged apps can also be hybrid if you want to utilize a web
view along with them we have an html five web view that can
point-two additional package content or external content as well now we
introduce this concept with windows eight and when we did we along with it
...a security policy that was custom
to windows so it was a windows web app security policy and
is anyone who likes writing code for just one platform?
As a web development community we are like that but I'll be honest at
...time there was no standard security policy that worked
across the browsers so we created one chrome created
one firefox created one they were all very similar but points in
a made frameworks especially have to write different code to run
in different applications well we're really excited because
now we have a wthree-c standard it's called the...the content
security policy that allows us to determine on a standard
wait what we're going to allow happen inside of our web apps so
we're real excited to support csp inside of web apps in windows
tag so that means you as...developer can determine
what the security policy is going to be on your pagewe have by default
the on the screen there you'll see the default security policy that we have.
And, then you can alter this as a developer so you can
make it tighter if you knows that you're not going to need a
...value for inline css we recommend you update your security
policy to follow that encoding standard as well so that
it locks down your app even more if you're using a
framework that might need some of these features that are blocked by default well then you can
lessen your security policy as well as the goal is to lead enhance
the developers and there's quite a few different things that you can
alter we have some examples on the screen you can basically determine
how you loader code where you loaded from in the type of code that you're
going to allow to run in your page so it's great for us to be able to support
...as...security policy in windows...match what
...a web developer are grammy writing for on any platform in the future.
All right so we're going to a quick download his remember we talked about how we
want-to make sure that web apps are simple to
build and that goes for hosted applications
to now I will be the first to admit that not all
websites are going to port to a package application
I'm going to actually pull up a blank app here and then I'm going to pull in the can
...so travel site that career had built now the
...so travel site is a single page application all of the code runs on a
single page this particular one doesn't even make any service
...so it's quite easy for me to take that same code that he had written
...on a web server.
And, move it into my package.
Now if you're using some back-end
rendering languages if you're, you're running ruby or java or
asp dot net where you're doing a lot of the rendering on the server-side a
package application might not be as simple of a transfer for
you as a developer now the good thing is the frameworks in the code that
you're using can be re-ran so I've gone hadn't dropped that n let's go ahead and run.
You know, I've...make one change.
I have a different page...I dropped in an index...html.
Go ahead and app update my manifests.
It's by default coining to default dot html.
So, change that the index.
That's how, you know, is really happening lab rank and there we go so the same can
...travel site that we had let me on the server is now...package application
...works great you can choose those dates who you want to go with ability to added
here your calendar so the same rendering engine that we
talked about running the same compatibility fixes that you get from microsoft edge
you get inside of your windows web app applications as well?
All right so let's talk a little bit about the new web view control we have been where passover
...write thanks chef now I'll talk a little bit about the
web you control that we've introduced with windows ten.
And, the web you control takes advantage
of microsoft edge new rendering engine it gets the new rendering engine
...continuous updates always up-to-date we've been listening to developer feedback and
taking it and trying to add to an already existing api set for the web you were trying to make that api
set really rich so you guys have the our to build the applications that you want and we've
aren't we've also improve performance by taking the web you often the
why thread so long-running script inside the web...won't hang the apps...
When you api that we've added and we feel like this is a powerful api ad web
...object and what ad level out object allows
you to do is inject custom components into the web...app
runtime of the application so you're able to determine the url before
navigating...view and decide what custom of windows runtime components
...you have included locally in your package you want to inject?
How this word before it was a little messy and we got a lot of feedback that people didn't
like it communication between the...in the web view was done
bypassing strings back and forth and this wasn't really a natural way so
we've given the web view of the ability to call native components from within
code running inside of it and to really show that I'll do a quick...demo?
One ad web...object.
So, let's which my computer.
There it's loading and what I've done here is I've actually added a local javascript page that
I'm running inside loading inside the web view so it's really easy to see and I can show the code but,
you don't have to do this you can look a navigate to a remote page inside the...
So, in order to really show this.
Our first show that the custom
...rt component that I have and this is just a csharp component of...for
...notifications I know I showed them our layer working in javascript but this is
that notifications working in csharp and this is just...tribe demo example but you could really
...any of windows runtime component you want to inject inside the...view.
In your code for your application you're able to detect the web
...navigation starting event and when you detector navigation starting for a web view?
You can look and we can listen for the url and if it's the right url
you're looking for you-can call...web...object onto the...view.
And, what ad web...object does
...that when...object that I showed the code for the
...notification and you give...a name that you're able to
...within the javascript code running inside the web?
So, just to show the javascript running inside the web view of just created a
...function called notify.
And, what that function calls is it directly often window object?
Calls the communicator object that I named it
...toast message from the csharp code so if I run this on my machine.
There's the application I have kind of like the application on top on the
bottom I have some web content loaded inside mobile view this is a common scenario and for
...web allowed object I'm able to hit notify and have a
...notification pop-up from the application?
Right and now switch back to the presentation the cover more of the new api is that we added.
Another new api that we added came directly from feedback that we got
...developers was the clear data api and we've heard that it's been
hard before to clear the cache of the application any remote content that was...
remain there so we added a clear data api to give developers of the ability to do that.
The new window event gives you notification as a developer for
...window dot open or things like that are called from within the web you so you can choose to popped
...new window or in the default browser.
We've added the permission requested api or events and what this event gives you
control over is permission requests like get user media in geo location in the
developers either able to defer to the user or auto
allowance denied that request?
Another thing that we added was the settings property.
And, the settings property controls is javascript enabled and is index
...enabled for the web...this is set before navigation?
And, the next thing...cover is just like hosted web apps the web
you has the ability to call into the windows runtime the windows
name space through the manifest through the manifests allow list...adverb
...object were also giving you more granular control where you're able to inject
at runtime any component you'd be able to call.
And, what that handed over to...
Yeah, we're really excited that the platforms really come together
in windows ten you can write all of your code on the web server or you
...course...nato's but we really appreciate how the
were able to blend the two together as well and the web...as well as the
hosted application allow you to do that where you can call that code directly and
your name code directly from your web code now a lot of
these changes have improve some of the stuff that we can do with
tooling in windows ten as well so cordova is a
...popular framework for us web
developers to use to build applications that work across platforms.
And, with the improvements that we have an windows ten or...introduce some
new scenarios for our developers now traditionally we've had the
packaged cordova applications where cordova has
...folder that lives in the package you put your web code in there and
then it's distributed along with the package to each of the stores?
We talked about our new hosted model in windows ten
...to is able to utilize this hosted model
to run a cordova app from the server as well which means you can
utilize cordova you could put the...js files on your server and run
your cordova app completely hosted the third thing is ...to
support the embedded scenarios for cordova what that allows you to do is if you
have an application already and you want to introduce some new functionality
with cordova or if you have an application that's native inches part of it utilizes
...you can now
imbed cordova it into your application which means
your application functions as it as...cordova is a portion of that application
that has access to the same api is the same cordova api that it does
in any other scenario so we're really excited to be able to support all these options
and cordova with windows ten web apps.
Now I another thing that we had talked about this morning the keynote is a javascript
frameworks that a bunch of our developers are working on and that's called
meaningful js we talked about how great hosted applications
are on windows how easy it is an how powerful they can be?
A number
platform support hosted applications already and the ones that don't can be
enabled with some work that we've done with cordova so this allows you to
manifold js allows you to take the same wthree-c standard that
you used to build the windows apps and then use that to
build applications for all those other platforms as well like I said when the nate when
the platform supports...hosted app natively will build you...app when it doesn't
we'll use cordova to...to build...application I think we
best defying show a little demo on how this works flood easier this
see to understand...
All right the first thing I'm going to do is ...run.
And, no, gs server so I already have this been going and this is just going to be
a local server and it's the same one that we had shown in the keynote
today.
So, I have it running here.
Shoots up and this is an application that I'm sure you've all seen those
...help you connect to other people wellthis is for us this helps us connect
to other frameworks so you can determine whether you
like a framework am whether you don't like a framework.
who knows maybe in the future those frameworks will be...like you back when that
be great all right so this is...sample application here I'm going-to go ahead and open
up another command-line?
I've already installed it installed is pretty easy and
pm manifold js and you have to have
node installed that's only requirement install node and then you can...pm...js.
So, I'm going to run it.
By the...manifold jazz...passing in my url in this case it's a local
house right so running there and then I'm going to turn on logging
so that we can see all the cool stuff...violet consul that size.
And, what's happening is it's going to go out to the server is going to
recognizer manifest file if you have...your server if you don't have one
on your server it'll pull some metadata from it any use that to
generate your application so you don't already have to have a manifests to use this
will build one for you and then if you have a
...go...in the images that you have listed there and bring them all local if
nonzero used to...ones that you can update yourself and what we amp with?
Is a application project for each of the different platforms so?
Go ahead and show you here so, for example,
when you go to chrome app...map all you really need is the manifest file and
...some of the images so we have that pulled down
for firefox you have a manifests file that lives on your servers so we build
that manifest file we take the hard part out of having to figure out how-to-do-it
for each platform allowed to do-it-yourself we also have read means that go in there for each of
them known for windows app I'm going-to go ahead and?
Visual studio and it's going to go ahead and bring that application of in visual studio
forming now why career showed earlier with the manifest
any images again are the only parts of this application and now
we're able to enable things like offline if here offline will give you messaging and things
like that but you don't need any additional code to run hosted app and...go ahead and run that?
You can see my server serving up the resources so it's at
runtime when you low your hosted application it goes out here web server
pulls the code that's out there so
you're users are always getting the most recent version and this pattern that we think
...so well on windows you can now use that same wthree-c
manifest to do it on all the platforms so we'll generate that
for-you we know that one of the great things about the web is that it's
a write once run everywhere platform and we want to contain
each encompass that we want to still lead the value of your web apps when
they're running inside a store applications so manifold js will help you build the
...for each of those platforms and allow
use a developer to focus on your website so we're real excited about that
we're continuing to work on it and we're always looking for
help so it it's a little call out there go to the website
and manifests are meaningful js dot com or argued have repo and,
there's a number of ways that you folks can help contribute to this to make it better and make it easier
for web developers so.
I think that's what we have here we have a bit of a summary of what we
talked about today so we started talking...out about
the universal windows apps in the fact that when you build a web app
you are universal windows app so you can expect that to run anywhere
that the universal windows apps friends we're excited to introduce hosted web apps and
give you the ability to use the code that's living out on the web as the basis for a
windows app while giving you access to the windows api is that can make
it differentiated on the windows platforms.
the improvements to the package apps with the new security bottle the new web view that we have
that...supports all of the new edge rendering engines and then of
course manifold js that we just demoed and that gives you the ability to
take this pattern and use it across platforms.
We have a few minutes left
...here to take questions so if you have one we're going to ask
and if you can set up to the microphone if you don't want to just shouted
out and will repeated...we want to make sure we...first question go ahead, yeah,
I want to know what you're going to do to prevent people from rapping other people's web
posted content and sites like...facebook but turning all the images
read...a great question so you know,
when we enable this that's one of the issues that we have to address as well so
we actually now in our store policy have a constant
review process which means that the apps are not only reviewed
and when they're first submitted to the market but they're also reviewed
throughout the lifetime of the app so that not only helps us catch you know,
web apps that don't belong because right if you're...to the market and you don't have the
writes for that but also like if an application and changes are starts breaking
overtime or something we're going to be able to pick that up so as far as whether it's
allowed or not is something that's going to be controlled from the content
owners so,
for example, if someone build a facebook application they weren't facebook,
facebook would have the right to a request that removal?
And, frat.
Yet I just wanted to clarify
...possible to have the...put that is the can
...contains the third-party code...loading scripts from some site
...facebook button stuff like that because currently it looks like it's
only the your...
No, that's actually not true so yes you can have a hosted web app
that contains third-party code it could be third-party bargains from other sites on the web
...just app include them in the application content your I roles so you define that
...part of your application and, you can also have local third-party code
that you can call from within your site that lives in your package.
...event server question about the manifold peace and hosted
versus package get and how that plays...ios yes so,
for example, for manifold it sounds like
...are hosted apps so it's still remote server and you can do
all your stuff but it's really the...with remote
...right but on apple...and now you if they believe that
it is a show application where the files hosted remotely as opposed to locally
tags so...apple as different policies than we do for the
stores so we can control that we whatever, you know,
they what I dissatisfied now we have a number of partners who use this and we have
worked with apple and without any problems now apples
policy from what I understand is that they don't want to be only?
Web hosted code they don't have a problem with it being hosted remotely
...they don't want to be the same experience that you have when you're on the website
from my experience it's been getting certification but and, I agree with
you we want to push we actually want to push from the standard perspective
on that because we think that...we know that...denying some great experiences that way and,
that's part of with the wthree standard they may take a different approach to
and, I'll, you know,
to have the hosted apps supported needs soluble web...supporter...their platform
wherein push really hard to make sure that there is a way to do it and based off of
the standard okay that makes sense and then but for now manifold is the hosted yet
so manifold is the way that we can make it work we actually utilize cordova
online ios to...refill what they
...support and,...if, you know,...know if you problems getting and we have partners
who have already done this in our in the doing well in
the ios store so we'd be happy to like make some connections and find out what they did.
So, with the packaged and hosted web apps obviously the
great things has access to the windows api is what about something like office so,
for example, I want to be able to...email from outlook in the app what about the usable?
Yes,...talk about that one.
Yes, it would be you'd have to write some code either locally or some javascript code on
the server to handle the content that you're dropping into the application but yes that's possible so
if you're dropping some content you'd have to write code obviously to handle by content and uploaded or
...or do whatever you like in your application but yes it is possible and
...a...code on server like javascript does
...to be isomorphic like using node or...we just?
A could just be client-side javascript right it's hosted on your server but,
it could be client-side encoded doesn't have to be server-side code thank you so if I wanted to
deploy a...internal application just for my company and not make it publicly available
in windows store is...a way to do that with those web apps.
...other rules and,
yeah, I know the rules so yes that is possible and actually if you want to do that
...you can deploy him to you can side...those apps just within your company and
...throughout your team.
But, you also get some exceptions so,
you're able to do things like...enterprise authentication and programmatic
access to the documents library if you were just...load and app you can get those
out access privileges if you were submitting to...store you could not if
you're in-store not if you're in the store but this is true for all windows
universe applications ok so if you if you decide loading...using
...business store you actually have less restrictions
...if it is through the general store.
Okay,
so, just my final question is...look like to deploy would you have to send out
a packaged file the users
...solemn their computer what would it look like.
So, you neither mr experts
in space so if we're not quite right I'll apologize
and there's a number of ways that you can do it side loading where you have a
packages that's distributed is one but I believe there's also
way to create a local market I know I microsoft we do that
in we actually have a number of our internal apps that use the hosted app
patter and...because they do deploys like every day right and
...which wouldn't be feasible to do that as a store as a native apps and
in we then have our corporate store that we can download apps from so we...happy to
plug-in with people who know more and ok...helpful thank you okay?
...up it loud so if I make a packaged application you showed how...I can
call native windows api using this ...was the
...object api
...can ical native ios ...stuff as well
although I need something like phone gap in addition to manifold js to
do that manifold uses cordova so yes you can
you can call the api...cordova has a set of api is
and then it has plugins that you can add so ...over that used to be called
...for folks are now okay...is phone yes,
...the...my question yes that's that you audio would have to do is add
been javascript portion of it to your website so it
...with your code and then you've got your api set their account thanks.
Just one question and you might have answered is already but
is local storage
working as well yes local storage works for both the web view and hosted web
...actually run this more offline or do you always need
an initial access to the internet so what the
...if it's a truly a hosted web app you could build local pages in the package where you can run
and offline only but if it's a truly a...web app coining two-year
...website you could use standard wthree-c technology offline technologies like index
db local storage app cash to build and offline experience and the first-time you
...it's obviously going to be remote and pulled down but if you have and offline experience
built in the next time you open the application...doesn't have to be online cool thanks?
...good question so the question is can you are extensions so this is
...javascript application object is the rendering engine
a javascript engines so it doesn't include like extensions browser helper
objects plug-in like flash and that none of that is supported inside the hosted
app just the html five.
And, I was just...more thing though you can actually,
you know, parent with native code which can give you that same
...functionality that you have with a extension.
...restrictions to popup windows.
Inside hosted web application or inside a web the
...hosted at.
Insider hosted app yes, they'll open up in the default browser inside the web
...able to handle them through an event that fires and choose to open a new web view
new window or whatever you'd like solvable that you would be a chrome that.
Right what web view is just a different container just has mormon api set
like enable you to handle things like windowed open popping of new windows inside the
...container...fire hosted app containeris
a lighter-weight container that doesn't have this api set that just...to...your web content?
Why is it possible to build a needed
components cplus-plus that uses a direct...and things like that and then
...api to javascript so that the javascript and orchestrate such a native components?
...dickens...yes you can so like, for example,
if you wanted to maybe use html for your markup or
something, you know, actually I don't read your much but html mark-up I care
but javascript basically having logicand, render
things natively okay so you can have a cplus-plus component that your javascript can
call...yes you can now wide one of the decisions you have to make is if
your depending on how you're going to display your application and if
you're hosted app then your cplus-plus will not be able to...to the
screen if you're a you know,...a traditional web apt and you can actually
have a web...in your cplus-plus app where yes
your cplus-plus in your javascript...can call each other no problem so this is a
couple different patterns depending on your scenario but what you're asking is possible.
Do you guys do any performance optimizations for startup for the hosted apps like I know package
dep skit by code...and stuff like that is there any facility to say
...user installs associate app...download some of these files like, you know,
my j query whatever things are...change?
And, you do any biker cashing or stuff like.
So, yeah, all that applies not
...installing before first launch but after first launch of
those obstinate optimizations from the web platform for the windows web platforms to apply.
I think that's it now we're going to be in the expert
...one more question...so you can...the last one.
Ok, the question was what kind of experience...you have with the legacy
site that is not responsive so it would appear as your site does its own
...similar things you gotta watch out for is if you have a dependency on flash.
It's not going to work in...or in the web view and we don't do
anything to make it responsive it's just going to render the way that it does.
Ok, will be...expert zone if you guys have any other questions for the next
half-hour otherwise thank you so much for joining us today and they give...
And, I give you played please do
...evaluation we would appreciate that the feedback.